<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Hyperplex</title>
		<description>A blog by Daniel Aditya Istyana which will talk about technology and news arounds Apple. Sometimes you've nothing to read here and of course it leads nowhere.</description>
		<link>http://hyperplex.co</link>
		<atom:link href="http://hyperplex.co/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>A Security Writer Says Goodbye to Android</title>
				<author>Daniel Aditya Istyana</author>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Security writer from Motherboard, Lorenzo Franceschi-Bicchierai:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is the fundamental difference between Android and iPhone. When there’s a bug on iOS, Apple patches it and can push an update to all iPhone users as soon as it’s ready, no questions asked.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;When the same thing happens with Android, Google patches and then… god knows when the AT&amp;amp;Ts, Verizons, HTCs, and Sonys of the world will decide it’s important enough that they should care and send you the update with the patch (though to their credit, they’re starting to care, mostly because having an updated OS is now seen as a competitive advantage). Hell, even Google-owned Nexus phones, which the company has full control over, haven’t been patched for Stagefright yet.[…]&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;You can keep your Android phone with that modified version of Android that your carrier or manufacturer has decided to put on it, and get security updates weeks late, or never (if you have a Nexus you’re better off, but who knows if Google is going to keep making Nexus phones in the future).&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Or you can root your phone and install the excellent and more swiftly updated Android-based operating system CyanogenMod on it. This is a good alternative, but it’s not trivial to install CyanogenMod, and updates for certain phones depend on volunteers, so, again, you might not get them as soon as you’d wish.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Or, lastly, you can give up, switch to Apple and buy an iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;As much as my old self will hate me, I’m going to choose the last option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I know it sucks when you have to join the dark side you hate but at least now you safe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 20:00:02 +0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/07/a-security-writer-says-goodbye-to-android/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/07/a-security-writer-says-goodbye-to-android/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Why I Don't Read Email in the Morning</title>
				<author>Daniel Aditya Istyana</author>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/roidrage&quot;&gt;Mathias Mayer&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Try this out for a week. Instead of opening email in the morning, open your notebook and write down two or three tasks that you want to get done before lunch. Then work through them. What you can get done in just two hours and by focusing only on work is pure magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why you don’t have to open and get inbox zero at the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 15:30:00 +0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/07/why-i-dont-read-email-in-the-morning/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/07/why-i-dont-read-email-in-the-morning/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Hide preference panes from System Preferences</title>
				<author>Daniel Aditya Istyana</author>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A nice little tip by Dan Morren about hiding prefeerence panes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/07/tip-hide-preference-panes-from-system-preferences/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/07/tip-hide-preference-panes-from-system-preferences/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Apple Music Sad Story</title>
				<author>Daniel Aditya Istyana</author>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marco.org/2015/07/26/dont-order-the-fish&quot;&gt;Marco Arment&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;iTunes is designed by the Junk Drawer Method: when enough cruft has built up that somebody tells the team to redesign it, while also adding and heavily promoting these great new features in the UI that are really important to the company’s other interests and are absolutely non-negotiable, the only thing they can really do is hide all of the old complexity in new places.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;With the introduction of Apple Music, Apple confusingly introduced a confusing service backed by the iTunes Store that’s confusingly integrated into iTunes and the iOS Music app (don’t even get me started on that) and partially, maybe, mostly replaces the also very confusing and historically unreliable iTunes Match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.loopinsight.com/2015/07/22/apple-music-is-a-nightmare-and-im-done-with-it/&quot;&gt;Jim Dalrymple loss his music library&lt;/a&gt; after Apple Music is launched to public. I never thought that Apple would get into this trouble before. I expected that Apple Music would be a great replacement of Spotify which I use before. Eventhough I’m not losing my music library, I have bad experience with Apple Music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This bad experience happens on iOS Music app. When I find a great playlist as suggested by Apple Music, I added them to my playlist collection but it showed nothing. There’s no songs on that playlist, even there’s no playlist cover as seen on search result. Next, I tried to create my own playlist based on my favorite songs of various artist. I created the playlist and go to the For You tab. I searched various songs and add them on the newly created playlist around 30 songs. But, again, it showed no songs. Bad. Pretty Bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know the purpose of baking Apple Music with iOS music apps but pardon me, can I categorize it as bloated software now? The interaction is confusing and there’s to many menu. Similarly with iTunes and I agree with Macro Arment on his blog post. I would love to see a new app, a standalone app for Apple Music on Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Messing up with personal stuff like musics or photos is indeed a terrible idea. If Apple do a great job with Photos app on Mac, why not taking the same path for Apple Music?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 17:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://hyperplex.co/article/2015/07/the-apple-music-sad-story/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://hyperplex.co/article/2015/07/the-apple-music-sad-story/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Jekyll, Github, and Dropbox</title>
				<author>Daniel Aditya Istyana</author>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;As everyone knows, this blog run on &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and the nice part about that is I just need to write the post in markdown formatted text and Jekyll take the rest. Jekyll also has many plugins so you can “hack” it to suit your needs. If you need to showcase your favorite musics, gadgets you own, achievment you get, you can use Jekyll collections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other advantages using Jekyll is it works out of the box with Github Pages.You can host your site on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; and will just render it okay. Furthermore, it’s free&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:fn1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:fn1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Other than that, Github let you keep track your site using its versioning system. Sounds nice, huh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s put things together. My Jekyll site live in my Mac local folder. Since I’ve to work using PC at my day work I need a service to let me synchronize files between that two machines so I can still write blog posts from my work PC. &lt;a href=&quot;https://dropbox.com&quot;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; to the rescue. Since I don’t want to put my entire site folder on my Dropbox so I just created symlink into it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all of this I have this site backup in Dropbox and Github server. I can now write on my PC at work, continue the drafts on my Mac and after I finish it, I have glynn command to deploy it to my hosting. Every changes is pushed to Github too and because I’m to lazy to type every single command into terminal, I make a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keyboardmaestro.com/main/&quot;&gt;Keyboard Maestro&lt;/a&gt; macros that hold every command into one and send a growl notifications when it finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, is everyone happy now? Me, definitely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:fn1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Hey, who doesn’t want free things? &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:fn1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 17:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://hyperplex.co/article/2015/07/jekyll-github-and-dropbox/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://hyperplex.co/article/2015/07/jekyll-github-and-dropbox/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Explain like I’m five&#58; Jekyll collections</title>
				<author>Daniel Aditya Istyana</author>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Ben Balter explaining how does collections in Jekyll work. I’m not using this features yet and haven’t figure out what collections I’m gonna add this site but let me put this here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 16:07:56 +0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/07/explain-like-im-five-jekyll-collections/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/07/explain-like-im-five-jekyll-collections/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Plotting Apple</title>
				<author>Daniel Aditya Istyana</author>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Drang has interesting takes on plotting Apple’s sales and revenue using Python/ Matplotlib code:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Every data point in the graph (except for the first three for each device) represents an average of the sales for four quarters: the current quarter and the previous three. The idea behind the averaging is to smooth out the strongly seasonal ups and downs in the raw quarterly data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 16:52:26 +0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/07/plotting-apple/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/07/plotting-apple/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>OS X 10.10 DYLD_PRINT_TO_FILE Local Privilege Escalation Vulnerability</title>
				<author>Daniel Aditya Istyana</author>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/i0n1c&quot;&gt;Stefan Esser&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;With the release of OS X 10.10 Apple added some new features to the dynamic linker dyld. One of these features is the new environment variable &lt;strong&gt;DYLD_PRINT_TO_FILE&lt;/strong&gt; that enables error logging to an arbitrary file.[…]. When this variable was added the usual safeguards that are required when adding support for new environment variables to the dynamic linker have not been used. Therefore it is possible to use this new feature even with SUID root binaries. This is dangerous, because it allows to open or create arbitrary files owned by the root user anywhere in the file system. Furthermore the opened log file is never closed and therefore its file descriptor is leaked into processes spawned by SUID binaries. This means child processes of SUID root processes can write to arbitrary files owned by the root user anywhere in the filesystem. This allows for easy privilege escalation in OS X 10.10.x.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore Esser explained that this isn’t patched on OS X 10.10.4 or the beta 10.10.5 but get fixed on OS X El Capitan. If you’re on OS X 10.10.4, Esser offer interim fix on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sektioneins/SUIDGuard&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; but since it isn’t official fix, install at your own risk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 15:39:41 +0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/07/os-x-1010-dyld-print-to-file-local-privilege-escalation-vulnerability/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://hyperplex.co/linked/2015/07/os-x-1010-dyld-print-to-file-local-privilege-escalation-vulnerability/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Apple Q3 2015 Financial Reports</title>
				<author>Daniel Aditya Istyana</author>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;From today Apple’s Q3 2015 financial reports:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPhone unit sales grew 35%, revenue grew even more up to 59%. It’s sold 47.5 million.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They sold 10.9 million iPad, lesser than two previous quarter with Q1 21.4 million, Q2 12.6 million. Let’s see if iOS 9 will give iPad sales bumps next quarter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mac is sold 4.8 million, slightly higher than previous quarter with 4.6 million. Market research firm IDC says that PC shipments &lt;a href=&quot;/linked/2015/07/pc-sales-continue-to-fall/&quot;&gt;drop up to 12%&lt;/a&gt; while its rival, Garner says it fell down to 9.5%. At the same time, Apple’s Mac sales continue grew by 9%. Meanwhile Peter Cohen on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imore.com/another-smashing-quarter-mac-sales-while-pc-sales-continue-drop&quot;&gt;iMore&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Apple earned 10.7 billion profit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to see some chart about Apple Q3 financial report then &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macstories.net/news/apple-q3-2015-results-49-6-billion-revenue-47-5-million-iphones-10-9-million-ipads-sold/&quot;&gt;Macstories&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://sixcolors.com/post/2015/07/appleq3results/&quot;&gt;SixColors&lt;/a&gt; have it for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s some interesting tweet about Apple Q3 financial report:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;“Other” was up $1B from last quarter. If Apple Watch ASP is $500, that’s 2 million watches.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Eric Slivka (@eslivka) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/eslivka/status/623592897137537024&quot;&gt;July 21, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;CNBC: TC says revenue in Greater China up ~112% in the quarter&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; MacJournals.com (@macjournals) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/macjournals/status/623591670940971008&quot;&gt;July 21, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Whatever estimates u have for the AppleWatch 1 thing is for sure, Apple sold more Watches in 2Q15 than all other smartwatch vendors combined&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Francisco Jeronimo (@fjeronimo) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fjeronimo/status/623609281821052928&quot;&gt;July 21, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Apple’s Other product category is now a billion dollars bigger this quarter. In other words, Apple Watch is a multi-$bn business already&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Steve T-S (@stroughtonsmith) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stroughtonsmith/status/623596899526905856&quot;&gt;July 21, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Also of note: Apple Watch was only in stores for /2 weeks/ of last quarter&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Steve T-S (@stroughtonsmith) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stroughtonsmith/status/623598890336563200&quot;&gt;July 21, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;This is unbelievable.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Apple&amp;#39;s cash pile is now almost as big as all of Greece&amp;#39;s GDP &lt;a href=&quot;http://t.co/HcGxtD8sMK&quot;&gt;http://t.co/HcGxtD8sMK&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?q=%24AAPL&amp;amp;src=ctag&quot;&gt;$AAPL&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://t.co/gART94Ryru&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/gART94Ryru&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; StockTwits (@StockTwits) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/StockTwits/status/623605380699017216&quot;&gt;July 21, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;iPhone is at the second highest price point it has ever achieved.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Horace Dediu (@asymco) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/asymco/status/623600168366116864&quot;&gt;July 21, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Apple saw the highest switching rate from Android they’ve ever measured, says Tim Cook.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Matthew Panzarino (@panzer) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/panzer/status/623599708867567616&quot;&gt;July 21, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I believe that Apple is the first company to break $1B in revenue for a wearable— and that&amp;#39;s in less than a quarter.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Carl Howe (@cdhowe) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cdhowe/status/623626585510424576&quot;&gt;July 21, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://hyperplex.co/article/2015/07/apple-q3-2015-financial-reports/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://hyperplex.co/article/2015/07/apple-q3-2015-financial-reports/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Theranos and Why It Matters</title>
				<author>Daniel Aditya Istyana</author>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theranos.com/&quot;&gt;Theranos&lt;/a&gt; the startup company which offer low cost lab test is received approval from Food and Drug Administration to perform herpes simplex 1 test outside the lab, according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2015/07/18/theranos-gains-fda-approval-to-test-for-herpes-outside-the-lab/&quot;&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;. The approval classified as CLIA Certificate waiver that will allow testing outside the lab with little error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Founder, Elizabeth Holmes when &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bizjournals.com/sanfrancisco/blog/biotech/2014/09/theranos-elizabeth-holmes-disrupt-blood-test.html&quot;&gt;talked at Techcrunch’s Disrupt Conferences&lt;/a&gt; told that Theranos aim to perform lab test with only small amount of blood which can be obtained from a simple finger prick at low cost. Since I work as an QA Officer of one clinical laboratory, Theranos quickly gets my attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I’m wondering what’s the technology behind Theranos device which make it’s possible to run the test with only few drops of blood. On a regular lab test, the patient’s blood need to be taken with venipuncture and processed to produce serum which we’ll run into analyzer. You’ve to go through pre-analytic, analytic and post-analytic process carefully to produce reliable and accurate result. When big analyzer perform test based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spectrophotometry&quot;&gt;spectrophotometry&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High-performance_liquid_chromatography&quot;&gt;HPLC&lt;/a&gt; even to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mass_spectrometry&quot;&gt;mass-spectrophotometry&lt;/a&gt; method to analyze sample, the question is what method does Theranos devices use to produce the result? The reliable result?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, about &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quality_control&quot;&gt;quality control&lt;/a&gt;. On regular lab test using analyzer, we need to perform quality control before we run patient’s sample. The purpose of running control is to ensure that all the test system which is used is running properly and produce acurate result. Again, the question is how the perform quality control on Theranos devices? Do they only need to be calibrated and you can use it o what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition besides method and quality control is cost. We all clinical laboratory try to give the best value for our customer. Ideally it would be low cost lab tes, quick turnaround time and acurate result. Maybe it’s no an apple to apple comparison since on the regular lab there would be a lot of additional material which is used in the process. But let me write this here, the new HSV1 which is newly got approved by FDA by Theranos costs $9.07, while today on our lab HSV1 costs approximately $22&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:fn1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:fn1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; using automated analyzer. Theranos’ HbA1C test which is used to monitor average glucose level in the blood for the last 2-3 months, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theranos.com/test-menu/test/82947&quot;&gt;cost $6.67&lt;/a&gt;, on us it’s $11.54.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course the higher price not just from the reagen but also the result of the additional material we use to perform the test from pre to post analytic such as syringe and vacuum tube to collect the patient’s specimen, tube to store the serum and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, Theranos technology could benefit us to the future. Performing lab testing outside laborartory with less errors means we could bring the device to remote areas. It would be more practical tho. The patient also could take the benefit from its system since it would be less pain when obtaining specimen, less blood to be taken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:fn1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Based on exchange rate this post is written since we use different currency &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:fn1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 21:15:19 +0700</pubDate>
				<link>http://hyperplex.co/article/2015/07/theranos-and-why-it-matters/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://hyperplex.co/article/2015/07/theranos-and-why-it-matters/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
